LEIGH ROGERS

Front-End Developer • UX/UI Designer • Digital Strategist

(734) 646-2884

limarkey@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/leighmrogers

github.com/LeighMRogers

ABOUT ME

A big picture strategist at heart, I love working on web projects from conception to final execution. With over 10 years of experience in digital strategy, website management, and now front-end development, I have focused on producing high-quality digital products aligned with organizational goals. This means I understand external marketing priorities as well as digital end-user needs.

In a UX/UI role, I look forward to applying software development skills to the planning and implementation process of building websites that I've known for over a decade.

EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School, Nashville, TN — *Front-End Software Developer and UX/UI Designer*

AUG 2019 - PRESENT

- Built single-page applications leveraging HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React with Git/GitHub version control
- Applied development fundamentals and principles through group and individual projects reflecting real world business problems
- Focused on user experience with intentional design around brand standards, efficiency, and smooth functionality
- Produced personas, journey maps, and prototypes based on user testing, market research, stakeholder goals, and scope assessment.
- Styled applications with CSS Flexbox and libraries like Bootstrap, Ant Design, and ReactStrap

Columbia Business School, New York, NY — *Communications Coordinator, Jerome A. Chazen Institute for Global Business*

MAY 2017 - AUG 2019

- Led strategy for the Chazen Institute's digital presence, integrating email marketing, paid social, and web content strategy
- Developed original content for Columbia Business School's thought leadership digital magazine, *Ideas at Work*
- Produced Chazen's student travel Wordpress blog, including content strategy, hiring student bloggers, quality control, and promotion
- Led strategy and execution of Chazen Institute's paid social media,

SKILLS

Tech: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Adobe CS, Google Analytics, AdWords, Google Apps

Systems: Visual Studio Code, Elcom CMS, Kentico CMS, Wordpress, Basecamp, Convio, Drupal, CreateSend, Trello, Eventbrite

Social: Facebook Ads, Twitter Ads, Instagram, Pinterest, Bitly, YouTube, Flickr, Buffer, Hootsuite, Sprout, Storify

Design: Figma, Ant Design, ReactStrap, Bootstrap, UX Design principles

PROJECTS

Safe Trip, Front-End Capstone github.com/LeighMRogers/safeTrip

A React-based application for travelers to create itineraries that display real-time country advisories from Travel-Advisory.info API

EDUCATION

Full-Time Front-End Developer & UI/UX Bootcamp

Nashville Software School, Nashville, TN, 2019-2020

Masters of Arts, Theology

Union Theological Seminary, New York, NY, 2006-2008

Bachelors of Arts, Religion

Denison University,

resulting in a 35% increase in Instagram followers in 2 years Granvill

• Contributed content to verified @Columbia Biz Twitter handle

General Board of Global Ministries, New York, NY — *Web Content Associate, United Methodist Committee on Relief (UMCOR)*

SEPT 2013 - NOV 2016

- Oversaw content generation and web strategy for <u>umcor.org</u> and <u>umcmission.org</u>, resulting in 50,000+ pageviews per month
- Executed digital marketing and web optimization strategies of #GivingTuesday campaigns enabling Global Ministries to raise \$12 million over 4 years
- Expanded donor access to mobile (raising \$2M more annually) by implementing UMCOR's first mobile adaptive site and third-party app
- Project managed and collaborated with freelance web designers and vendors for website redesign look/feel and user experience
- Built HTML-based email newsletters sent to over 100,000 subscribers
- Led all aspects of social media for Global Ministries and UMCOR, boosting Facebook and Twitter reach 40% in less than 3 years
- Managed UMCOR Google AdWords Grant of \$10,000 ad spend per month

United Methodist Women, New York, NY — *Web Content & Public Relations Associate*

OCT 2008 - AUG 2013

- Administered <u>unitedmethodistwomen.org</u> and in-house social network <u>umwonline.org</u>
- Project managed website content audit and migration of 15,000+ web pages to a new content management system
- Led two on-brand website redesigns in 2013 and 2010, improving usability, functionality, and brand identity for UMW members
- Designed trainings for members and staff on core aspects of digital strategy, including writing for the web, social media marketing, and web hosting
- Developed and oversaw multi-platform social media presence; Grew Facebook fans from 300 to 25,000 in 5 years
- Led organizational media relations, crisis resolution, and press lists
- Oversaw digital and external communications for a variety of local and national events, such as board meetings, leadership trainings, and member conventions

Granville, OH, 2002-2006

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Basic conversational **Biblical Hebrew:** Basic written

LEADERSHIP

Chair, Social Committee, Columbia Business School

NOV 2017 - AUG 2019

Led committee creating social and collaborative opportunities for staff

Sub-Chair, Board of Governors, Religion Communicators Council

APR 2013 - MAR 2016

Played lead role in organizing all aspects of annual award ceremony.

Sub-Chair, Racial Justice Task Force, United Methodist Women

NOV 2011 - SEP 2013

Led process creating values statement for staff working relationships within the context of racial justice

AWARDS & HONORS

Award of Excellence 2016

"UMCOR Responds to Syrian Refugees," from Religion Communicators Council.

Award of Excellence 2013

Pro-Peace Subway Ad Campaign, from Religion Communicators Council.

Award of Excellence 2012

unitedmethodistwomen.org, from United Methodist Association of Communicators.